Guide to the Martin Shubik Papers, 1938-2017 and undated RL.01181
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Service, 1956-2014; undated; 1
  - Conferences and Organizations, 1957-2014; undated; 1
    - Hong Kong, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Hong Kong, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Hudson Institute, undated (Box 127)
    - In Cash We Trust, New Haven Register, 2002 (Box 52)
    - Incontri di Rocca Salimbeni, Siena, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Institute of Global Management Studies newsletter, 2001 (Box 52)
    - International Security Program Luncheon Seminars, 1993 (Box 6)
    - International Security Studies and Arms Control-Defense Policy Seminar, Yale University, undated (Box 7)
    - It's Not Just a Game, 2008 (Box 7)
    - Kenya, Ford Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 48)
    - Kenya, Ford Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 48)
    - Latin America Symposium, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Lecture at The Institute of Advanced Study, Vienna, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Lecture, inkuBATor wiedzy invitation, Warsaw, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Lectures given, 1988-1991 (Box 5)
    - List of assumptions by one panel member, undated (Box 7)
    - List of participants, undated (Box 7)
    - Mackintosh Lecture, Queens University, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Mathematical-Arms Control and Disarmament Agency Conference, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Matrix Games: Non-Cooperative Equilibria and Cooperative Games Interlinked, undated (Box 125)
    - Meeting of the members of the Advisory Board of Economic Notes, Siena, 1990 (Box 51)
    - Memorandum of Strategic Studies Group of Naval Operations, 1999 (Box 51)
    - Mini Conference on Theory of Games, 1983 (Box 127)
      Includes conference program
    - Minister des Affaires Internationales Seminar, Quebec, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous professional service, 2005-2013 (Box 126)
    - Money, Time, and (Dis)Equilibrium, 2011 (Box 125)
    - Monte dei Paschi di Siena Conference, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Morgenstern, Oskar, Vienna, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Museum of Money and Financial Institutions, 1999; 2 folders (Box 127)
      Includes files related to establishing the museum
    - Museum of Money project, 2000 (Box 52)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1998 (Box 127)
      Includes grant proposals
    - NSF Gaming Grant proposals, 1967-1972 (Box 122)
    - NSF Grant proposal, 2000 (Box 122)
    - NBER Conference, undated (Box 126)
    - NBER Conference Economics of Art Museums, 1989 (Box 5)
    - NBER Conference on General Equilibrium and Economic Theory, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Newspaper article regarding the Tax History Museum, Nixon's Tax Return, A Cyberspace Treasure, New York Times, 2004 (Box 52)
    - Office of Naval Research proposal, Economic Warfare and Analytical Methods in Force Mix and Command and Control, 1985 (Box 49)
    - Office of Naval Research, budgets and contracts, 1983-1984 (Box 49)
    - Office of the Secretary of Defense, OSD Naval War College, 1993 (Box 51)
    - Orientation Seminar Manufacturing Systems Simulation, 1959 (Box 2)
    - ORSA Panel on Threats, 1966 (Box 121)
    - Oskar Morgenstern Symposium on Mathematical Economics & Econometrics, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Oskar Morgenstern Vorlesung, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Presentation on Game Theory, undated (Box 127)
    - Project Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems Research, 1981 (Box 121)
    - Project proposal, Quantitative Approaches to Avoiding Accidental War, 1987 (Box 49)
    - Proposal for Conference on The Purposes, Goals and Validation Procedures for Military Gaming, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Proposal for research and teaching by Jerome Braden, 1991 (Box 50)
      Includes draft proposal to the Spencer Foundation
    - Proposal, An Integrated Social and Economic Analysis of the United States, 1970 (Box 47)
    - Proposal, Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems Research, 1970s-1980s (Box 49)
    - Proposal, Crisis Stability Games, 1990 (Box 50)
    - Proposal, Global Security: Quantitative Methodologies for Avoidance of Accidental War, 1989 (Box 50)
    - Proposal, Models, Simulations, and Games: Theory, Substance, Evaluation and Applications, undated (Box 48)
    - Proposal: Seminar in Defense Analysis and Arms Control Methodology, undated (Box 126)
    - Q2, interview, Can We Manage without Markets, 2007 (Box 52)
    - RAND Conference, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Referee evaluation, Limits to Science or Limits to Epistemology by Duclauf, S., 1996 (Box 51)
    - Report on working group of Geanakoplos, Karatzas, Shubik and Sudderth, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Research proposal to NSF, Experimental Gaming in a Time-Sharing Automated Laboratory, 1971 (Box 48)
    - Research proposal, Competitive Enterprise Economics, 1989 (Box 49)
    - Santa Fe Institute, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Santa Fe Institute 2006 Annual Report (Box 52)
    - Santa Fe Institute Meeting, 1990s (Box 126)
    - Santa Fe Institute Science Board meeting, 1997 (Box 51)
    - Schedule of events, Naval War College, 1971 (Box 48)
    - Science Advisory Board, 2002; 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Scientific Decision Making for Tomorrow's Marketing, London, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Seminar on The American Market for the Visual Arts and High Quality Crafts, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Seminar on War Gaming, 2000 (Box 126)
    - Seminar, Mathematical Institutional Economics, Santa Fe, 2006 (Box 7)
    - Seminar, Participation of Mandelbrot, 1999 (Box 7)
    - SFI Economics Program, undated (Box 126)
    - SIAH Institute for Mathematics and Society, proposals etc., 1980s (Box 50)
    - Siena and Copenhagen, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Siena Conference Economic Notes, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Siena Conference Risks Involving Derivatives and Other New Financial Instruments, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Siena Workshop, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Singapore Economic Review, 2009-2010 (Box 126)
    - Soviet Trip/Uretsky, 1976-1977 (Box 122)
    - Stenographic Transcript of Proceedings of the Westinghouse Marketing Seminar, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Stony Brook, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Stony Brook, 1984 (Box 49)
    - Symposium on Game Theory, University of Cincinnati, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Symposium on Global Modeling, Bader, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Symposium on Just Winners and Losers: The Application of Game Theory to Corporate Law and Practice, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Symposium on Strategic Planning, 1981 (Box 127)
    - Symposium Taking Decisions: Can Information Technology Help?, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Synopsis of Pollack meeting, undated (Box 52)
    - Talk, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Talk, undated (Box 7)
    - Talk on Strategic Marketing and Minimal Financial Institutions, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Talk on What is an Application and When is Theory a Waste of Time?, New Orleans, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Talk Risk, Society, Politicians, Scientists and People, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Talk, A Survey of Strategic Market Games, Stony Brook, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Talk, Can a Central Bank's Interest Rate Policy Control Inflation?, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Talk, Game Theory and Operations Research, undated (Box 7)
    - Talk, Time and Money, undated (Box 7)
    - Talks/Presentations by Shubik, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
    - Temple University, 1996; 2001 (Box 126)
    - The Econometric Society, election of officers and council, 2002 (Box 52)
    - The Interest Rate Dilemma, 1983 (Box 5)
    - The Museum of Money and Financial Institutions, business plan, 2002 (Box 52)
    - The Practice and Theory of Money, 2014 (Box 125)
    - The Present and Future of Game Theory, 2010 (Box 125)
    - The Soros Foundations, 1995 (Box 126)
    - The Theory of Money and Financial Institutions, Talk in Vienna, 1980 (Box 5)
    - The Third Conference on Games, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Third International Conference on Operational Research, 1963 (Box 2)
    - TIMS-IST Conference on Adaptive Systems, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Triangle Universities Security Seminar, University of North Carolina, 1994 (Box 7)
    - UCSB, 1995; 2001 (Box 126)
    - University of Maryland (McGuire) Lecture, 1990 (Box 6)
    - University of Nottingham Conference, undated (Box 126)
    - Viability of Players in Repeated Games, 2007; undated (Box 125)
    - Wesleyan University Seminar, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Williams College Museum of Art, visiting committee membership categories, 1988-1991 (Box 49)
    - Workshop on Economic Conflict and National Security Research, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Workshop on Gaming as an Aid in Policy Formulation and Implementation, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Yale University Workshop on Environment and Security, Invitation List, undated (Box 7)
    - Yale: Defense Economics and Military Operations/ International Arms Control, 1984-1991 (Box 122)
  - Consulting, 1956-1995; 2
    This subseries includes alphabetically arranged files related to Shubik's consulting activities for various companies and organizations, and files documenting his expert witness testimony.
    - Alpha Group, Inc., 1968-1970 (Box 127)
      Includes documents from Shubik's time serving on the board
    - Amos, Michael P., criminal case, 1991 (Box 50)
    - Anglo Energy, Inc., 1987 (Box 127)
      Includes documents related to investment in company
    - B.F. Goodrich, 1964 (Box 127)
    - Blecker v. Araskog, 1984 (Box 127)
      Includes files related to expert witness testimony
    - Business game development proposals, 1960-1961 (Box 46)
    - Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems Research, report, 1987 (Box 49)
    - Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems, research report, 1980s (Box 49)
    - Clipping, OTAN meeting, 1964 (Box 47)
      Item in French.
    - Conference and trip reports in the context of Shubik's engagement with General Electric Company, 1957-1960 (Box 46)
    - Consultancy activity, RBC project correspondence, proposal etc., 1995 (Box 51)
    - Consultancy and research activity to the Bureau of the Budget, US Government, 1960s-1990s (Box 51)
    - Correspondence on professional appointment at UC Davis and Stanford University, 1980 (Box 49)
    - Department of Defense, 1983 (Box 49)
    - E-J Electric v. Leviton Manufacturing, 1983 (Box 127)
    - Engagements, research and consultancy activity in Latin America (Chile, Colombia, Brazil), 1960s-1970s; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Expert witness duties, 1974 (Box 48)
    - Expert witness duties, 1979 (Box 48)
    - Expert witness duties and legal involvements, 1980s (Box 50)
    - Expert witness duties and other involvement in legal issues, 1982 (Box 49)
    - Fidelity Daily Income Trust, 1979 (Box 127)
    - Hoberman v. Manufacturers Hanover Trust Co., 1974 (Box 127)
    - Improved Techniques for Film Rental Prediction, 1971 (Box 127)
      Includes consulting report
    - Improving Regulatory Effectiveness in Federal/State..., Success Factor Evaluation Panel, 1977 (Box 48)
    - Johns-Manville Corp. Bankruptcy, 1982 (Box 127)
    - Lane v. National Fence, 1973 (Box 127)
    - Lee v. Carter, 1976-1979; 2 folders (Box 127)
    - Letter to the editor from Carlos Garcia Mata about M. Shubik, 1959 (Box 46)
    - Lynch v. Vickers Energy, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 127)
    - M. L. Hurni, letters, 1956-1960 (Box 46)
      Shubik's work for General Electric
    - Memoranda, research notes on gaming, simulations, RAND with DeWeerd, Marshall, etc., 1970s (Box 48)
    - Memorandum from Task Force Meeting on Gaming, International Institution for Applied Systems Analysis, 1978 (Box 48)
    - Memorandum, A Note on Extending the Use of FAST-VAL, RAND, 1970 (Box 47)
    - Memorandum, deterrence study, 1961 (Box 46)
    - Memorandum, Notes on the Gaming Evaluation Project, 1970 (Box 47)
    - Merrill Lynch v. Andre, 1981 (Box 127)
    - Nasdaq Market-Makers Antitrust Litigation, 1995 (Box 127)
    - Nuclear Regulatory Commission, 1970s (Box 49)
    - Nuclear Regulatory Commission, panel on Success Factor Evaluation, 1976-1977; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Police department visit, 1967 (Box 47)
    - Professional service agreement, IBM, 1962-1963 (Box 46)
    - Professional service agreement, RAND, 1969 (Box 47)
    - Report study, National Security and the World Financial System, with Ikle, Fred C., 1980s (Box 49)
    - Research report, Information, Duopoly and Competitive Markets: A Sensitive Analysis, Vienna, 1972 (Box 48)
    - Research study, Concepts and Principles of Pricing in General Electric, 1957 (Box 46)
    - Science Applications, Inc., 1979 (Box 127)
      Includes consulting agreement
    - Shell Centre, London, 1969-1972 (Box 47)
    - Shell strategic planning seminar, (General Electric), 1957 (Box 46)
    - Sikorsky, 1964 (Box 127)
      Includes documents related consulting and consulting agreement
    - Social Systems, Inc., 1977 (Box 48)
    - Social Systems, Inc., 1980; 2 folders (Box 127)
      Includes files related to Shubik's service on the board
    - Solitron Devices, 1983 (Box 127)
    - Strategic Considerations in the Color TV Tube Market, 1964 (Box 127)
    - System Development Corporation, 1962-1963 (Box 127)
      Includes documents related to consulting agreement
    - Taitt Evaluation, 1987 (Box 127)
    - Transcripts of audio recordings, games, game theory, RAND with Brewer, Shubik, Paxson, etc., 1970s (Box 48)
- Research and Notes, 1944-2004; undated; 1
  This series includes Shubik's notes and correspondence for research projects, notes from classes taken as a student, and portion of his collection of academic writings by others. Research notes include files projects on game theory, simulation, and auctions, among other topics.
  - Class Notes, 1947-1954; undated; 1
    Includes files for classes taken by Shubik at the University of Toronto and Princeton University arranged alphabetically. Of note are files for classes taught by Oskar Morgenstern and Jacob Viner.
    - Business Cycles with Oskar Morgenstern, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Cycle Theory, undated (Box 2)
    - Economic Theory with F. Lutz, Fall 1949 and Spring 1950, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Exams at the University of Toronto and Princeton University, 1947-1950 (Box 2)
    - International Economics, Fall 1948-Spring 1949, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
    - International Trade with Jacob Viner, Fall 1949 and Fall 1950, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Mathematics, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Money with Henry Wallich, Spring 1950 (Box 2)
    - Princeton fourth year reading list, undated (Box 2)
    - Statistics, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Statistics, Fall 1949 (Box 2)
    - Unsolved Problems in Mathematical Economics, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Research, 1950-2000s; 2
    This subseries contains files for Shubik's various research projects, arranged alphabetically, including work on game theory, simulation, auctions, and bargaining. This subseries also includes Shubik's research reports from his time at IBM.
    - Artificial Intelligence, gaming theory, etc. (bibliographies), undated (Box 111)
    - Auctions, bidding (notes, clippings, manuscript in unknown hand, translation of Talamanca work), 1960s (Box 111)
    - Bibliography, select publications, 1973 (Box 111)
    - Bibliography, select publications, 1989 (Box 111)
    - Bibliography, select publications, undated (Box 111)
    - Bibliography, Shubik, 1973 (Box 111)
    - Bibliography, Shubik (notes, articles), 1971 (Box 111)
    - Bibliography, various economists, undated (Box 111)
    - Bidding (correspondence), undated (Box 112)
    - Bidding, simple models, (notes), undated (Box 112)
    - Business and regulation (notes), undated (Box 112)
    - Games, undated (Box 112)
    - Gaming (unidentified notes), undated (Box 112)
    - Gaming and simulation bibliography, undated (Box 112)
    - Historical approaches to production models (table), 1980s (Box 112)
    - IBM Research Reports binder, 1962-1970; 3 folders (Box 124)
    - Imputation, two-person bargaining (proof, galley), 1950; undated (Box 112)
    - Mathematical finance models (notes), 2000s (Box 112)
    - Multiple equilibria (notes), undated (Box 112)
    - Notes on the Getty-Levine Theorem, 1991 (Box 127)
    - Nuclear stability, strategy (notes, correspondence), undated (Box 112)
    - Problems of pareto optimal surface by Frisch, H. (notes), 1969 (Box 112)
    - Production in economic models (notes), 1999 (Box 112)
    - References, 1974-1978 (Box 43)
    - References, bibliographies, 1972-1977 (Box 43)
    - Reviews, abstracts, references, 1977-1981 (Box 43)
    - Socio-economic and international simulations (notes), 1964; c. 1979 (Box 112)
    - Switching in a market with taxation and transaction costs (notes), undated (Box 112)
    - T.E.M.P.E.R (notes, review), 1967 (Box 112)
    - Truancy (article by unidentified author), undated (Box 112)
    - URI (notes), undated (Box 112)
    - World financial crises, world debt (notes), undated (Box 112)
  - Writings by Others, 1944-2004; undated; 3
    Includes select articles, book chapters, and books used in Shubik's research arranged alphabetically. Includes works in English, French, German, Chinese, and Russian. Chinese and Russian titles are at the end of the list.
    - Aker, J. and Anderson, J., Operations Research in the Warsaw Pact Armed Forces, 1974 (Box 112)
    - Amihud, Y., Bidding and Auctioning for Procurement and Allocation, 1976 (Box 156)
    - Amir, R., Aumann, R., Peck, J., and Wooders, M., Games and Economic Behavior in Honor of M. Shubik, 2004 (Box 112)
    - Anderson, R., Quick Response Equilibrium, 1983 (Box 112)
    - Averch, H., Evaluating Models: trends and prospects, 1972 (Box 112)
    - Barbut, M., Monjardet, B., Ordre et Classification Algébre et Combinatoire, 1970 (Box 159)
    - Beckmann, M., Künzi, Z., Kooperative Spiele und Märkte, Lecture Notes in Operations Research and Mathematical Systems, 1971 (Box 160)
    - Beder, M., A Futures and Options Market for Agricultural Products in Mexico, 1993 (Box 112)
    - Berge, C., Théorie Générale Des Jeux A n Personnes, 1957 (Box 159)
    - Bernd, J., Mathematical Applications in Political Science, II, 1966 (Box 156)
    - Bewley, T., Interviews as a Valid Empirical Tool in Economics, 2004 (Box 127)
    - Bouchard, J. P. and Sornette, D., Derivatives Trading, 1996 (Box 112)
    - Brams, S., Davis, M., and Straffin, P., The Geometry of the Arms Race, 1979 (Box 112)
    - Brown, A., The Great Inflation 1939-1951, 1956 (Box 156)
    - Buchler, I., Applications of the Theory of Games in the Behavioral Sciences, 1966 (Box 156)
    - Chamberlin, E., Monopoly and Competition and their Regulation, 1954 (Box 156)
    - Chernov, E., Berrigan, D., Dimensionless numbers and the assembly rules for life, 1991 (Box 127)
    - Clark, J., Mathematical and Physical Tables, 1944 (Box 156)
    - Cohen, J., Can Human Irrationality Be Experimentally Demonstrated?, 1981 (Box 112)
    - Courbis, R., Compétitive et Croissance en Économie Concurrencée, 1975 (Box 159)
    - Cyert, R., A Behavioral Theory of the Firm, 1963 (Box 156)
    - Debreu, G., Theory of Value: An Axiomatic Analysis of Economic Equilibrium, 1959 (Box 156)
    - De Finetti, B., La Teoria dei Giochi, 1963 (Box 112)
    - Dodds, P. et al., Information exchange and the robustness of organizational networks, 2003 (Box 127)
    - Dorfman, R., Application of Linear Programming to the Theory of the Firm, 1951 (Box 156)
    - Dunlap and Associates, Mathematical Models of Human Behavior: Proceedings of a Symposium, 1955 (Box 156)
    - Edwards, W., Lindman, H., and Savage, L., Bayesian Statistical Inference... (signed copy), 1963 (Box 112)
    - Einzig, P., Primitive Money in its Ethnological, Historical, and Economic Aspects, 1951 (Box 156)
    - Fellingham, J., Quantum Information and Double-Entry Accounting, 2002 (Box 127)
    - Filar, J. and Raghavan, T. E. S., A Matrix Game Solution of the Single-controller Stochastic Game, undated (Box 112)
    - Filar, J., The Completely Mixed Single-Controlling Stochastic Game, 1983 (Box 112)
    - Filar, J., The Travelling Inspector Model, 1983 (Box 112)
    - Frank, M., The Braess Paradox, 1981 (Box 112)
    - Frank, W., Ten Great Software Myths, 1978 (Box 127)
    - Fudenberg, D. and Maskin, E., The Folk Theorem in Repeated Games..., 1984 (Box 112)
    - Fundamentals of War Gaming, 1966 (Box 127)
    - Goldhamer, H., Social Mobility (signed reprint), 1968 (Box 112)
    - Gordon, J., Shareholder Initiative and Social Choice... (signed reprint), 1991 (Box 112)
    - Gordon, T.J., Helmer, O., Report on a Long-Range Forecasting Study, 1964 (Box 127)
    - Granger, C., Morgenstern, O., Predictability of Stock Market Prices, 1970 (Box 156)
    - Guiasu, S., Malitza, M., Coalition and Connection in Games, 1980 (Box 156)
    - Güth, W., Kooperation in Marktwirtschaften, 1974 (Box 160)
    - Haberler, G., Prosperity and Depression, 1941 (Box 156)
    - Heller, W., Holdings of Idle Money Balances in General Equilibrium, 1972 (Box 127)
    - History of Political Economy, 1986 (Box 127)
    - Holler, M., Power, Voting, and Voting Power, 1982 (Box 156)
    - Honkapohja, S., On the Efficiency of a Competitive Monetary Equilibrium with Transaction Costs, undated (Box 127)
    - Institut Français de Polémologie, Études Polémologiques, 1977 (Box 159)
    - Jacot, S., Stratégie et Concurrence, 1961 (Box 159)
    - Kachigan, S., The Game: A Lesson, 1984 (Box 156)
    - Kantorovich, L., Dynamic Models of Scientific-technical Progress (signed reprint), 1974 (Box 112)
    - Klipstein, D., The Contributions of Edsel Murphy..., 1969 (Box 112)
    - Krelle, W., Präferenz-Und Entscheidungstheorie, 1968 (Box 160)
    - Kreps, D. and Wilson, R., Sequential Equilibria, 1982 (Box 113)
    - Kuhn, H., Classics in Game Theory, 1997 (Box 156)
    - Kurz, M., Equilibrium in a Finite Sequence of Markets with Transaction Cost, 1974 (Box 127)
    - Lasswell, H., Decision Process, 1956 (Box 127)
    - Leonard, R., Von Neumann, Morgenstern, and the Creation of Game Theory, 2010 (Box 156)
    - Lerner, A., Economics of Employment, 1951 (Box 156)
    - Management Review, 1957 (Box 127)
    - Manual War Gaming, 1969 (Box 127)
    - Markov, M., Science and the Responsibility of Scientists (signed reprint), 1975 (Box 113)
    - McKinsey, J., Introduction to the Theory of Games, 1952 (Box 156)
    - Mensch, A., Theory of Games: Techniques and Applications (Box 157)
    - Milnor, J. and Shapley, L., On Games of Survival, 1955 (Box 113)
    - Morgenstern, O., Collaboration between Oskar Morgenstern and John von Neumann on the Theory of Games, 1971 (Box 128)
      Includes early draft of Morgenstern's reflections on development of game theory
    - Morgenstern, O., Economic Activity Analysis, 1954 (Box 157)
    - Morgenstern, O., On the Accuracy of Economic Observations, 1963 (Box 157)
    - Morgenstern, O., The Question of National Defense: A Critique of Our Military Preparations and Policies, 1959 (Box 157)
    - Morgenstern, O., Knorr, K., Heiss, K., Long Term Projections of Power: Political, Economic, and Military Forecasting, 1973 (Box 157)
    - Moulin, H., Game Theory for the Social Sciences, 1986 (Box 157)
    - Nelson, R. and Winter, S., An Evolutionary Theory of Economic Capabilities and Behavior (manuscript), 1982; 4 folders (Box 113)
    - Owen, G., Game Theory, 1968 (Box 157)
    - Peck, J. Shell, K., Liquid Markets and Competition, 1988 (Box 128)
    - Perroux, F., Unités Actives et Mathématiques Nouvelles, 1975 (Box 159)
    - Phillips, E., Functions of a Complex Variable with Applications, 1945 (Box 157)
    - Powers, M., Sin, Short-selling, Taxes, Bubbles and the Price of Shares, undated (Box 113)
    - RAND Corporation: The First Fifteen Years, 1963 (Box 128)
    - Rosenthal, R., Discussion of Lloyd Shapley's Noncooperative General Exchange, undated (Box 113)
    - Sahi, S., The Noncooperative Equilibria of a Trading Economy..., 1987 (Box 113)
    - Sanghvi, A., The Asympotic Behavior of some Sequential Games, 1973 (Box 114)
    - Schermerhorn, R., Society and Power, 1961 (Box 157)
    - Schleicher, H., Staatshaushalt und Strategie, 1971 (Box 160)
    - Selten, R., The Chain Store Paradox, 1974 (Box 114)
    - Sherman, R., Psychological Difference Between Ambiguity and Risk, 1974 (Box 128)